{"status":"Success","data":{"question_paper2":[{"question_no":"1","question":"Name the District where most number of Railway Stations in Kerala?","option1":"Ernakulam","option2":"Palakkad","option3":"Trissur","option4":"Thiruvananthapuram","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"2","question":"In which district is 'Ponmudi Dam' situated","option1":"Alapuzha","option2":"Idukki","option3":"Pathanamthitta","option4":"Kollam","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"3","question":"Which Road is the first Rubberised Road in Kerala?","option1":"Kottayam - Kumali","option2":"Kottayam-Erumelly","option3":"Thiruvananthapuram-Kanyakumari","option4":"Edappally-Palakkad","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"4","question":"The first floating ATM in India is established by SBT at:","option1":"Kochi","option2":"Alapuzha","option3":"Quilon","option4":"Thiruvananthapuram","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"5","question":"Which prime minister inaugurated 'Silent Valley' National Park?","option1":"Rajeev Gandhi","option2":"Indira Gandhi","option3":"V.P.Singh","option4":"Jawaharlal Nehru","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"6","question":"How many Time Zones are in India?","option1":"One","option2":"Two","option3":"Three","option4":"None of these","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"7","question":"Which names below is not related to river 'Kavery'?","option1":"Andhra Ganga","option2":"Telugu Ganga","option3":"Dheshini Ganga","option4":"The Ganga","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"8","question":"_______ commonly known as 'October heat':","option1":"North-East Monsoon","option2":"North-West Monsoon","option3":"East-West Monsoon","option4":"Cyclones","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"9","question":"The Red colour of red soil due to the presence of:","option1":"Potassium Permanganate","option2":"Iron Oxide","option3":"Iron sulphide","option4":"Magnesium Sulphate","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"10","question":"Corbet National Park is situated in which state?","option1":"Madhya Pradesh","option2":"Orissa","option3":"Uttarakhand","option4":"Jharkhand","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"11","question":"The Book 'The First War of Independence' was written by:","option1":"Mangal Pandey","option2":"V.D.Sarvaker","option3":"S.N.Sen","option4":"Nirud C Chaudari","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"12","question":"Who is known as Father of Indian Economy and Indian Politics?","option1":"Gopala Krishna Gokhale","option2":"Dada Bai Navaroji","option3":"Lal Lajapath Rai","option4":"Swami Vivekananda","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"13","question":"Jalian Valabagh Massacre was took place on:","option1":"13th April 1913","option2":"13th May 1913","option3":"13th April 1914","option4":"13th May 1914","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"14","question":"Head Quarters of National Investment on Ayog (NIA)","option1":"Kochi","option2":"Bangalore","option3":"Mumbai","option4":"New Delhi","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"15","question":"The motto of SPG (Special Protection Group):","option1":"Bravery Dedication Security","option2":"Truth wins","option3":"Sathyameva Jayathe","option4":"Security at always development","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"16","question":"cover Page of Indian Constitution was designed by:","option1":"Navindra Nath Tagore","option2":"Nandalal Bose","option3":"Nandal Gholh","option4":"B.N.Rao","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"17","question":"The first Democracy in the world:","option1":"India","option2":"Greece","option3":"Britian","option4":"Switzerland","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"18","question":"Who is known as 'Modern Budha'?","option1":"Sardar K.M.Panikar","option2":"Sardar Vallabhai Pattel","option3":"Dr. B.R.Ambedkar","option4":"Sree Sakaracharya","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"19","question":"The first acting President of India:","option1":"V.V.Giri","option2":"B.P.Jetty","option3":"Dr.S.Radhakrishnan","option4":"K.R.Narayanan","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"20","question":"University Grand Commission (UGC) started during ______ Five Year Plan","option1":"First","option2":"Second","option3":"Third","option4":"Fourth","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"21","question":"The first chairman of National Human Right Commission:","option1":"Justice K.G.Balakrishnan","option2":"Justice Rahmath Mishra","option3":"Justice J.K.Kushi","option4":"Justice Krian Joseph","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"22","question":"Which country passed the rights to information Act first?","option1":"Switzerland","option2":"China","option3":"Sweeden","option4":"India","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"23","question":"International Woman's day is on:","option1":"March 8","option2":"September 5","option3":"December 1","option4":"May 8","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"24","question":"Dowry prohibited Act was passed by the Parliament in:","option1":"1961","option2":"1965","option3":"1962","option4":"1951","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"25","question":"The first Vigilance Commissioner of India:","option1":"N.Srinivas Rao","option2":"B.Srinivass Iyyar","option3":"R.N.Prasad","option4":"Jullier Muhammed Sadir Ali","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"26","question":"2014 Common Wealth game held in:","option1":"Glasgow","option2":"Inchion","option3":"Brazil","option4":"India","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"27","question":"Father of Malayalam film:","option1":"Adoor Gopalakrishnan","option2":"J.C.Daniel","option3":"M.T. Vasudevan Nair","option4":"Prem Nazir","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"28","question":"Who is known of 'Kerala Scott'?","option1":"C.V. Raman Pillai","option2":"K. Kelappan","option3":"G. Sankarakurup","option4":"S.K. Pottakkad","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"29","question":"Who said \"Knowledge is power and Ignorance is death\"?","option1":"Fracis Bacon","option2":"Swami Vivekananda","option3":"Budha","option4":"Aristotle","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"30","question":"Who wrote the famous book'The Path of Power'?","option1":"Dr.Annie Besant","option2":"Margrat Thatcher","option3":"Indira Gandhi","option4":"Benazir bhutto","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"31","question":"Long walk to Freedom is an Autobiography of:","option1":"Mahatma Gandhi","option2":"Nelson Mandela","option3":"Martin Luther King","option4":"Adolf Hitler","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"32","question":"Boz is the pet name of:","option1":"Charles Dickens","option2":"George Bernard Shaw","option3":"Shakespeare","option4":"Jawaharlal Nehru","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"33","question":"Zulu's are tribal people lives in:","option1":"India","option2":"South America","option3":"South Africa","option4":"Astralia","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"34","question":"oneirology is the study of:","option1":"Birds","option2":"Insects","option3":"Dreams","option4":"Propnorms","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"35","question":"Which among the following is not an isotope of Hydrogen?","option1":"Protium","option2":"Deuterium","option3":"Tritium","option4":"Curium","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"36","question":"Number of groups in the modern periodic table:","option1":"18","option2":"16","option3":"7","option4":"13","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"37","question":"Most abundant metal in the human body?","option1":"Nitrogen","option2":"Calcium","option3":"Phosphorus","option4":"Iron","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"38","question":"Yellow colour of turmeric is due to:","option1":"Carotene","option2":"Curcumine","option3":"Chlorophyll","option4":"Xanthophyll","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"39","question":"The chemical name of vitamin E:","option1":"Tocopherol","option2":"Phylloofuinone","option3":"Calciferol","option4":"Retinol","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"40","question":"The substance which are used for artificial raining:","option1":"Silver Bromide","option2":"Silver Iodine","option3":"Silver Nitrate","option4":"Sodium Chloride","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"41","question":"Animal having heaviest liver but lightest heart:","option1":"Elephant","option2":"Cow","option3":"Pig","option4":"Rabbit","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"42","question":"Normal blood cholesterol level of human body:","option1":"80-120 mg\/100 ml","option2":"150-260 mg\/100 ml","option3":"100-180 mg\/100 ml","option4":"150-150 mg\/100 ml","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"43","question":"In which part of the human body is Ricket Effects?","option1":"Eyes","option2":"Born","option3":"Muscles","option4":"Immune system","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"44","question":"Father of Indian Railway is:","option1":"Lord Dalhousie","option2":"Lord Rippon","option3":"Lord Wellesley","option4":"Lord Curzon","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"45","question":"As mosquito is to Riggler cockroach is to:","option1":"Maggol","option2":"Cater Piller","option3":"Nymph","option4":"Chitin","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"46","question":"Name the bird, which can fly backwards:","option1":"Duck","option2":"Ostrich","option3":"Kiwi","option4":"Humming Bird","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"47","question":"Father of Green Revolution:","option1":"Norman Borlaug","option2":"Dr. M.S.Swaminathan","option3":"William Gaud","option4":"Varghese Kurian","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"48","question":"Unfinished Dream is a book written by:","option1":"M.S. Swaminathan","option2":"Varghese Kurian","option3":"Salim Ali","option4":"Sachin Tendulkar","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"49","question":"Leading producers of milk in India is:","option1":"Kerala","option2":"Rajasthan","option3":"Andra Pradesh","option4":"Gujarat","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"50","question":"First malayalee Woman to appear in Indian Postage Stamp:","option1":"P.T.Usha","option2":"Alphonsamma","option3":"Annie Besent","option4":"Dr. Arunthathi Roy","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"51","question":"World Telecommunication day is observed on:","option1":"October 9","option2":"May 17","option3":"May 7","option4":"June 5","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"52","question":"Which part of the Indian constitution is called magnacarta of India or key stone of the constitution?","option1":"Part III","option2":"Preamble","option3":"Article 19","option4":"Article 24","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"53","question":"Father of Indian Planning is:","option1":"M.N.Roy","option2":"Narayanan Agarwal","option3":"Amarthya Sen","option4":"M.Viswaswarayya","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"54","question":"Hypermetropia means:","option1":"Short sightness","option2":"Long sightness","option3":"Astigmatism","option4":"Night Blindness","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"55","question":"The Keralite whose Birth day and Death anniversary are celebrated as holiday by Kerala Government:","option1":"Sri.Narayana Gru","option2":"Sir KRISHNA","option3":"sREE sankaran","option4":"Ayyankali","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"56","question":"Who was the founder of Nair Service Society(NSS)?","option1":"Veluppilly Naolesan","option2":"Sri.Narayana Guru","option3":"Mannath Padmanabhan","option4":"Kannan Nair","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"57","question":"Who was the First General Secretary of SNDP?","option1":"Sri.Narayana Guru","option2":"Kumaranasan","option3":"V.T.Bhattathirippad","option4":"K.Kelappan","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"58","question":"A.K.G Statue is situated at:","option1":"Kannur","option2":"Thiruvananthapuram","option3":"New Delhi","option4":"Payyannur","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"59","question":"Malabar Economic Union was founded by:","option1":"Dr. Palpu","option2":"Kesavan","option3":"C.V.Raman Pillai","option4":"Panikkar","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"60","question":"Father of cloning:","option1":"Ian Wilmutt","option2":"Griger Mendel","option3":"Watson","option4":"Har Govind Khorana","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"61","question":"In a democracy every one ______ obey the laws of the country.","option1":"can","option2":"will","option3":"may","option4":"ought to","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"62","question":"Mr. Gupta accompanied by his two sons, ______ going on a tour abroad.","option1":"are","option2":"has","option3":"is","option4":"were","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"63","question":"______ furniture arrived for you this morning.","option1":"the","option2":"a","option3":"an","option4":"some","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"64","question":"What is paper made?","option1":"of","option2":"with","option3":"on","option4":"upon","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"65","question":"When I left the house, I _____ all the rooms.","option1":"locked","option2":"had locked","option3":"has locked","option4":"have locked","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"66","question":"He said,\"I shall come\"- this can be rewrite into indirect speech as:","option1":"He said that he shall come","option2":"He said that he might come","option3":"He said that he would come","option4":"He said that he should come","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"67","question":"Arrange into proper sentence:\r\nan old man, saw, I, crossing the road","option1":"An old man crossing the road, I saw","option2":"I saw an old man, crossing the road","option3":"I crossing the road, saw an old man","option4":"An old man saw, I crossing the road","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"68","question":"Honesty is a virtue. It is an exceedingly wise policy:","option1":"too","option2":"next","option3":"but","option4":"equally","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"69","question":"He left the room open, the underline word here is:","option1":"an adjective","option2":"an adverb","option3":"a noun","option4":"a verb","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"70","question":"If I had a million pounds.","option1":"I had bought an estate","option2":"I will by an estate","option3":"I would buy an estate","option4":"I would have bought an estate","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"71","question":"The car ______ at the gate of the house.","option1":"looked out","option2":"pulled up","option3":"set in","option4":"gave in","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"72","question":"An ignorant person, especially one pretending to have knowledge is called:","option1":"iconoclast","option2":"ignoramus","option3":"inebitrate","option4":"misogamist","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"73","question":"I _______ my favorite book.","option1":"reread","option2":"overread","option3":"preread","option4":"antiread","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"74","question":"The antonym of 'dismis' is","option1":"discharge","option2":"disprove","option3":"repeal","option4":"reinstate","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"75","question":"The toy was very attractive, but nobody knew its mode of operation, the substitute for the underlined words is:","option1":"locus standi","option2":"in tato","option3":"modus operandi","option4":"pro tempore","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"76","question":"The passenger had an ______ with the ticket examiner for 10 minites.","option1":"Alternative","option2":"alternate","option3":"alternation","option4":"altercation","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"77","question":"The plural of rhinoceros is:","option1":"rhinoceroses","option2":"rhinoceros","option3":"rhinocerosis","option4":"rhinocerosess","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"78","question":"Pick out the correct spelling:","option1":"Memorandem","option2":"memorendem","option3":"memorandum","option4":"memorendam","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"79","question":"My grand father usually had forty winks after lunch the underlined words mean:","option1":"a short walk","option2":"a short sleep","option3":"read for a while","option4":"a short talk","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"80","question":"The word 'Fradulence' means:","option1":"Congregation","option2":"custom","option3":"correction","option4":"corruption","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"81","question":"1\/2+1\/3+ ____ =1","option1":"5\/6","option2":"1\/6","option3":"2\/3","option4":"1\/3","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"82","question":"Articles are brought for Rs.400 and sold for Rs.560. Find the profit percentage?","option1":"45","option2":"60","option3":"40","option4":"65","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"83","question":"The difference between simple interest and compound interest on Rs.2500 for 2 years at 6% per annum is:","option1":"Rs.9","option2":"Rs.90","option3":"Rs.2509","option4":"Rs.191","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"84","question":"If A:B = 7:9 and B:C = 3:5 then A:B:c is =","option1":"7:9:5","option2":"21:35:45","option3":"7:9:15","option4":"7:3:15","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"85","question":"A train 150m long running at a speed of 60km\/hour takes 30 seconds to cross a bridge. What is the length of the bridge?","option1":"200m","option2":"500m","option3":"3.5km","option4":"350m","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"86","question":"A can do a piece of work in 6 days and B in 12 days. If they work together, in how many days will they finish the work?","option1":"4 days","option2":"5 days","option3":"12 days","option4":"10 days","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"87","question":"The mean of 50 values is 15.What will be the new mean if each value is multiplied by 2?","option1":"15","option2":"30","option3":"50","option4":"100","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"88","question":"A wire in the form of a circle of radius 84cm is cut and bent in the form of a square. If \u312b is taken as 22\/7, the side of the square (in cm) is:","option1":"88","option2":"110","option3":"132","option4":"None of these","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"89","question":"Find the next number in the series: \r\n3,4,8,17,33, ____","option1":"63","option2":"65","option3":"66","option4":"58","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"90","question":"Paper is to Pen as garden is to:","option1":"apade","option2":"lawn","option3":"flowers","option4":"health","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"91","question":"If + means x, - means \u00f7 , x means -, and \u00f7 means +, then 9+8\u00f78-4x9=:","option1":"26","option2":"17","option3":"65","option4":"11","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"92","question":"Which of the following will come next?\r\nBHL, DJN, FLP, _____","option1":"HNR","option2":"HOS","option3":"IOS","option4":"INR","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"93","question":"Find the odd one out:","option1":"Veena","option2":"Flute","option3":"Violin","option4":"Sitar","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"94","question":"If TEACH is coded as XIEGL, STUDY will be coded as:","option1":"WXYHC","option2":"WXZID","option3":"WXYHV","option4":"WXVHC","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"95","question":"Pointing to a man, a woman said,\"His mother is the only daughter of my mother\". How is the woman related to the man?","option1":"Daughter","option2":"Mother","option3":"Sister","option4":"Grandmother","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"96","question":"Manu walks 5km towards North, then turns to his left and walks 4km. He again turns left and walks for 5km. At this point he turns to his left and walks for 5km. How many km is he from the sarting poin","option1":"5 km","option2":"2 km","option3":"3 km","option4":"1 km","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"97","question":"What is the correct time when the mirror image of the clock reads 7.15?","option1":"9.20","option2":"2.35","option3":"4.45","option4":"9.25","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"98","question":"How many 8's are there in the following sequence which are preceded by 5 but not immediately followed by 3?\n58375863854584765583587558285","option1":"8","option2":"5","option3":"7","option4":"4","answer":"4"}]}}